The Networking exam tests your foundational
knowledge of networking concepts and
administration. It is a conceptual exam, meaning
that you do not need to possess the knowledge of
a full-fledged network administrator. Still,
you need to know basic networking concepts
and how they fit into the grand scheme
of building and maintaining a network.
To that point, we will take you through
this course as if you work for TekkieVets,
an IT consulting company, and you are a candidate
to be promoted from a help desk support agent
to a junior-level network administrator. To that
end, we will cover the basics of network building
and administration among these five exam domains:
Networking Fundamentals, Network Infrastructure
Network Hardware, Protocols and Services, and
Troubleshooting. Make sure you pay close attention
to the whats, as in what are these different
parts of a network? To follow along with the
live demos in this course, you will want to have a
couple of Windows devices connected to each other,
or at least one Windows device,
an installation of Windows server,
and if you can get your hands on a wireless access
point to configure, all the better. Getting some
hands-on practice will solidify your knowledge
of the concepts we are covering in this course.